Finding Aid for the Albert Lewin Papers PASC.0314
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4. Stage Productions, (ca. 1946-1990); Boxes 40- 46
  - Gift Horse (The)
    - Script, (1959) (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Script, (1962 Dec 13) (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Script, (no date) (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Script, (1954 Jul 5) (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Script, (no date) (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Script- Author's Master, (no date) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Script materials, (1946 Feb) (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Notes and rewrites.
    - Script Materials (folder 1 of 2), (1964 Jan) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Script Materials (folder 2 of 2), (1964 Jan) (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Gift Horse (The) - annotated script
    - Script, (no date) (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Script, (1964 Jun 15) (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Stuff about trip to NY in here too. Should keep or return to family?
    - Script, (no date) (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Script, (no date) (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Gift Horse (The) - script
    - Script, (no date) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Trashman
    - Big Sweat Over Swizel Mahoney (The) also called An Ounce of Convention - notes (folder 1 of 2), (1967 May) (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Working title for Trashman.
    - Big Sweat Over Swizel Mahoney (The) also called An Ounce of Convention - notes (folder 2 of 2), (1963, 1967) (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Big Sweat Over Swizel Mahoney (The) play script, (no date) (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Original draft play script, (1976 Jan) (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Also includes drawings for set design.
    - Original File - notes and script material, (no date) (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Original Handwritten Notes and Manuscript, (1976 Feb-Apr) (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Research, (1974) (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Revised Master - script, (1976 Aug 26) (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Revised Original Manuscript, (1976 Sept 15) (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Script, (no date) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Script, (1978) (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Script, (1990) (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Script, (no date) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Script, (1978) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Script, (no date) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Script Materials, (1982 Oct 4) (Box 44, Folder 5)
      Includes suggested music plot and Act II.
- Series 5. Gag Files, (no dates); Boxes 54-55
  The Gag Files series consists of jokes, gags, and/or one-liners handwritten on 3x5 index cards. The file was created by Lewin and is organized by topics and/or subjects. It appears that the file is in its original order; however, it is not clear how the topics are organized. Many of the topics appear to be divided into subject divisions related to the topic.
  - Topical gags, jokes, and/or one liners written on 3x5 index cards (Box 54)
  - Topical gags, jokes, and/or one liners written on 3x5 index cards (Box 55)
- Series 6. Book Projects, (ca. 1979-1980); Boxes 46, 53
  The Book Projects series consists of materials relating to the novel that Lewin co-wrote with Norman Panama entitled, The Glass Bed. The series contains typescript manuscripts, reviews, publicity, and a small number of letters regarding the project. The Glass Bed is adapted from the motion picture screenplay by Lewin and Panama titled Hollywood and Vine. See also the Motion Pictures Series for material related to Hollywood and Vine. The series is arranged alphabetically by file titles which reflect the content of the folders.
  - unspecified
    - Glass Bed (The) - copyedited revisions (safety copy) - photocopied typescript manuscript by Lewin and Panama, (1980 Jan 28) (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Glass Bed (The) - correspondence regarding publication., (1979-1980) (Box 46, Folder 6)
      With agreement between Panama and Lewin and William Morrow & Co.
    - Glass Bed (The) - photocopy of originals, typescript manuscript, (1979 Nov 15) (Box 46, Folder 4)
      With holograph notes.
    - Glass Bed (The) - reviews and publicity (folder 1 of 3), (1980) (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Clippings and holograph notes.
    - Glass Bed (The) - reviews and publicity (folder 2 of 3), (1980) (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Clippings.
    - Glass Bed (The) - reviews and publicity (folder 3 of 3), (1980) (Box 37, Folder 6)
      Holograph and typescript version of Answers- Questions about the new novel.
    - Hollywood and Vine - photocopy of manuscript, (no date) (Box 47, Folder 3)
      Working title for Glass Bed.
    - Audio Cassette work tape, 1979 (Box 58)
- Series 7. Unidentified Projects, (ca. 1957-1962, the bulk is not dated); Boxes 29, 30, 34, 39, 41
  The Unidentified Projects series contains a mixture of partial and complete scripts, notes, idea, outlines, and a small number of letters all of which could be related to possible motion picture, radio, television, and/or other writing projects. The capacity in which Lewin was involved with these projects or if they were produced is unknown. Additionally, there are a small number of writings for what appears to be dinner speeches and roasts for politicians written in the 1970s. The files in the series are arranged alphabetically by project title.
  - The Bloodhounds Tale script, (no date) (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Charlie McCarthy and Edgar Bergen material, (no date) (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Fine Kettle of Grandchildren (A) - script, (no date) (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Freelance Materials, (no date) (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Hoffingham Hotel, (no date) (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Irresistible - script materials, (1959-1962) (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Step outline, notes, and letters about the project.
  - Micronauts (The) ideas, (1977 Feb-Apr) (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Political, (1972, 1977, 1982) (Box 36, Folder 12)
    Notes and drafts for what appears to be written remarks for others to present at political-type social events. Events appear to be for James Corman, Tony Bielenson, Ted Gutman, George McGovern.
  - Skotnicki Story (The) - script, (1957 Sept 16) (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Show of Truth by Lewin and Styler., (no date) (Box 35, Folder 8)
    Typescript manuscript.
  - Unidentified Projects
  - Wonderful Heel (The) book by Albert Lewin and Burt Styler, (no date) (Box 34, Folder 14)
    Appears to be play script.
- Series 8: Business Files, (ca. 1946-1982); Boxes 37, 46
  The Business Files series contains a small amount of fragmentary records documenting business dealings related to Lewin's career. Included are agency contracts between Lewin and assorted representative agencies. Most of the contracts appear to be generic and very few include information about specific projects. Additionally, there are a small number of bulletins and rosters pertaining to the Writer's Guild of America strike in which it appears Lewin was involved in some capacity. There is no specific arrangement to the series.
  - Agency contractual aggreements, (1946-1977) (Box 46, Folder 1)
    Assorted contractual agreements with various agencies.
  - Writers Guild of America Strike, (1981) (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Bulletins concerning the strike and rosters of what appears to be picketer's names.
- Series 9: Correspondence, (ca. 1942-1950); Box 34
  The Correspondence series contains a small number of letters to and from Lewin related to business and/or personal matters. It appears that Lewin may have considered some of the letters legal-type documents. Additionally, there are items involving Lewin and his longtime writing partner Burt Styler. The series is arranged alphabetically by folder titles which reflect the content of the folders.
  - Al Lewin business and personal items, (1948-1952) (Box 34, Folder 13)
    With miscellaneous receipts that appear unrelated to correspondence.
  - Burt Styler correspondence, (1950-1951) (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Famous Artists Corporation (letter to Charles Feldman from Lewin and Styler), (1950 May 1) (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Legal Documents, (1942-1947) (Box 34, Folder 9)
    Appears to be related to professional dealings. With letter to and from Mickey Rooney regarding Blessed Events.
  - Letters to Answer, (1946-1947) (Box 34, Folder 10)
    Some items in French.
- Series 10. Printed Materials, (1940s); Box 46
  The Printed Materials Series contains a small amount of press clippings related to Lewin and/or the projects he was involved in. There is no specific arrangement to the series.
  - Press clippings mentioning Lewin, (1947-1951) (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Variety (4 issues), (1949-1950) (Box 44, Folder 6)
- Series 11. Audio Recordings, ca. 1970-1990; Boxes 54-63
  The Audio Recordings series is partially processed and contains cassette tapes and audio reel recordings of meetings and/or phone conversations which were recorded by Lewin. Many of these home recordings are labeled with dates and/or topic and are related to projects in which he was involved. There is no specific arrangement to the series. PLEASE NOTE: The sound recordings are restricted and use of the material requires production of listening copies.
  - Audio reels of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1965-1971) (Box 64)
    Many of the items are labeled with dates and or topic. RESTRICTED ACCESS: use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
  - Audio reels of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1965-1971) (Box 63)
  - Cassette tapes of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1972-1984) (Box 59)
    Includes: radio interviews
  - Cassette tapes of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1971-1972) (Box 62)
    Includes: "Marriage Contract", Lourdes, Tarzana, Felix, Flip, Jack Benny Recollects, Jeff Groberman, In the Beginning
  - Cassette tapes of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1970-1972) (Box 61)
    Box 61: on tape "human fly, Panama talks
  - Cassette tapes of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1970-1975) (Box 60)
  - Cassette tapes of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1979-1990) (Box 56)
    Many of the items are labeled with dates and or topic.
  - Cassette tapes of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1976-1980) (Box 58)
  - Cassette tapes of meetings and/or phone conversations recorded by Lewin, (ca 1974-1979) (Box 57)
    Includes: All in the Family; Different Strokes; Chico and the Man; Prospectors; Imp; Quincy; Stewardesses.
- Series 12. 63rd Infantry Division Service, (1943-1950); Boxes 34, 37, 46
  The 63rd Infantry Division Service Series contains materials related to Lewin's military service during World War II. Included are letters from fellow war veterans who served in the Division; a manuscript contrived by Pfc Alan Kellock; a photograph of the 63rd choir performing in Baton Rough, Louisiana; 10 copies of a newsletter contrived by Lewin; and a small number of Blood and Fire, a newspaper-like newsletter by and about the division. The series is arranged alphabetically by folder titles which reflect the content of the folders.
  - 63rd Infantry Division Special Service (Miscellaneous), (1943-1944) (Box 37, Folder 5)
    Folder originally titled Miscellaneous. Can Training Films be Used More Effectively in the Army manuscript by Pfc Alan Kellock, copies of newsletter contrived by Lewin, and letters from other members of Division. Also contains still of 63rd Infantry.
  - Blood and Fire newspaper-like newsletters, (1943 Nov-Dec) (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Letters to and from Lewin with fellow war veterans from the 63rd Division, (1949-1950) (Box 34, Folder 11)
    Appears to be letters between Lewin and others who served in the 63rd Division during World War II.
- Series 13. Esther Lewin Papers, (ca. 1946); Box 36
  Esther Lewin papers contain a holograph manuscript of a publication entitled, Little Billy Boat, written by Esther Lewin, Albert Lewin's wife. Additionally, there is a press clipping of an interview with Mrs. Lewin from the mid-1940s.
  - Little Billy Boat materials and press clipping, (1946-1947) (Box 36, Folder 7)
    Appears to be a holograph children's book manuscript with illustrations.